In part one, I asked you some personal
questions. Let's talk about food. What
is your favorite type of food? Um, my
favorite type of food. Um, there's a lot
of food out there. If I really had to
dig deep, um, I'd say I like fast food.
Um, definitely like my poutines and
burgers. Um, barbecue food, too. Uh,
ribs. I think that's probably one of my
favorite foods. How often do you eat at
restaurants? Eating at restaurants? Um,
I think it depends on the week, you
know. Um, having a bad week, um, maybe a
little bit more, three, four times.
Having good week, maybe I'm at home a
little more, maybe just one, two times.
I think it depends.
Do you prefer home-cooked meals or
eating out? Home-cooked meals. Um, I
think everyone loves home-cooked meals
at the end of the day. Uh, it's great to
come home to a nice filling meal.
Definitely some of my favorite
home-cooked meals for sure. Definitely
remember my mom having home-cooked
meals. That's probably the best part.
Now, let's talk about uh communication.
How do you usually communicate with your
friends? Communicate with my friends?
I'd say Instagram and Snapchat on social
media is for the most part how I talk to
them. Why is that? Um I think it's more
so just my age group with what I'd like
to talk to and uh the easiest way to
communicate. It's very popular. It's
easy. Okay. You prefer texting or
calling? It depends on who I'm talking
to. Um, some of my close friends, I do
enjoy calling them. Um, I find it a
little bit more personal, but um,
daytoday I'd say I text more than I
call. How would you say communication
has changed compared to the past? Um,
definitely social media. It plays a huge
role in it. Obviously, uh, in the last
couple years, there's more and more
social media and more and more people on
it. So, uh, I think that's changed the
most. you know, people used to be more
face to face talking and now you're
talking on social media a lot more. It's
changed a lot in that way. Okay. Now,
let's talk about your hobbies and
interests. So, what is it? What is your
favorite hobby and how often do you do
it? Um, my favorite hobby, I'd have to
say in the summertime would definitely
be golfing. Um, I love getting out on
the golf course. It's uh beautiful out
there, very relaxing. It's uh it's great
to do. In the winter time, I'd say
snowboarding would be my favorite. Um, I
don't get out as much as I'd like to,
but uh, it's one of my favorite things
to do. Okay. Have your hobbies changed
since, uh, childhood? Um, definitely
have changed since childhood growing up.
Um, finding new friends, new interests.
They've changed. I, uh, used to play
soccer quite a bit as a child. Um, not
so much anymore. Um, more so just the
golfing. Um, take it easy.
Uh, why do you think they've changed?
How do you think they've changed? Um, I
think just growing older, you know,
things change. Um, obviously as a child,
you have a lot of different friends, a
lot different interests. You know,
everyone wants to grow up and be a
professional soccer player, but at the
end of the day, not everyone can do
that. So, I I think just getting older,
maturing has changed them for the most
part. Do you prefer hobbies that require
more physical activity or more mental
engagement? Definitely. Growing up
playing sports, I'd say physical
activity. Um, having that little bit of
competitiveness behind myself. I
definitely enjoy having a little bit of
fun, you know, trying to win. No, not
everyone always does, but I enjoy it.
Why do you think more physical than
mental? Um, I think uh I think that's
where my strong suits are. Definitely on
the physical side of things. All right.
So, that concludes part one. We're going
to move to part two. And in part two,
I'm going to give you a topic. And I'd
like you to talk about the topic for two
minutes. Before you talk, you'll have
about a minute. So you can write things
down. I have a pen and paper here. You
can make notes if you wish. Do you
understand? Yes, I understand. Okay. You
can take some paper and a pencil to make
notes. And your topic is describe a time
when you helped a stranger.
So, let me start the clock and you can
have one minute.
All right. Go ahead.
Okay, that was a minute. Um, you can
start speaking now. Um, times I've
helped a stranger. I think it's kind of
hard to pinpoint just uh one time I've
helped a stranger. I think over the past
uh you seem to help strangers a lot more
than you uh remember you do. just the
simple things, opening doors for people,
um giving them compliments, um just
talking to someone when they need it. I
think that's more uh helping a stranger
than uh anyone could ever believe. Um
it's definitely different. And of
course, you have your family growing up,
helping them, maybe not strangers, maybe
family friends or friends. Uh I feel
you're always helping someone at the end
of the day. Just talking to someone.
Communicating is uh definitely a big way
to help strangers. anyone day can maybe
not be going so great and having a small
conversation can definitely just help
them out. Um, opening the door, giving a
suggestion to someone, um, just starting
a conversation, I would say it's
probably the best way to help someone
nowadays. A lot of people are tied off
and don't want to talk to anyone, but
just offering that little bit of, "Hey,
how you doing?" I think that's a great
way to help strangers. And definitely
things I've done in the past is just
talk to people. But I enjoy talking to
people. I find it uh helps quite a bit.
And then obviously, you know, just your
day-to-day things um at work, helping
customers. Um they're strangers to me at
the end of the day. Helping them, trying
to fix all their problems, make sure
they have great customer service. Still
helping strangers. I think there's more
things you do in life that you don't
realize that end up helping strangers.
Okay, that concludes part two. We're
going to move to part three. and we've
been talking about helping strangers and
I'd now like to ask you some questions
related to this. So why do people help
strangers? Um I think that's a very good
question. Why do people help strangers?
Um I think it's to almost make
themselves feel good at some point. Um
everyone likes, you know, trying to
offer someone some help and uh it
definitely makes yourself and and make
yourself look good. Um, it's not always
easy, but I I think that's why people do
it. Self-gratitude. I think that's why.
Do you think people today are less
willing to help others compared to maybe
people in the past? Um, I think so. Um,
I think in the past people were brought
up on the uh I help you, you help me.
Um, I think things are a little divided
nowadays and not everyone's willing to
help everyone. Uh, I think that should
change. But going back to your question,
yes, I do think it's different from the
past from now.
Should children be taught to help
others? Children should definitely be
taught to help others. Um, obviously
from a young age, they're very
influenced um by all their peers and
adults. They should be taught how to
treat people right and how to talk to
people and and how to help people they
don't know and uh just uh general
things.
Do you think large organizations or
individuals have a bigger responsibility
to help society? I think they do. Um
they're playing a huge role in people's
lives nowadays. Uh for sure. And um they
have huge platforms that they should be
using for the better to help those
people. Um I think that's the best way
to best way to put that. They should be
more influenced on everyone else and
trying to help everyone else. They have
a big a big voice. they should
definitely be using it.
In your opinion, does helping others
always make a difference? It doesn't
always make a difference. No. Um, not
everyone's willing to accept the help or
wants to help. Um, but all you can do is
try as a human being. That's that's all
you can do. It's a it's a difficult one
for sure, but everyone needs a little
bit of respect and trying to help them
out. I think that's the right thing to
do, but not everyone's uh willing to do
that. All right. Well, thank you very
much. This is the end of the speaking
test. I'm going to take a couple minutes
to go over what we went through here. Do
you want to know what band score you'll
get in the IELTS speaking test? Perhaps
you want to improve your performance and
prepare yourself for the real test. Then
why not book an online mock test with us
that will last for 25 minutes, 12
minutes of the test itself, and 13
minutes of comprehensive feedback. Plus,
we'll give you useful tips on how to
make your performance better. So, we
know how to help you. Join us.
Okay, that was a lot of talking. Do you
have any questions? Thank No, thank you
very much. I really appreciate that you
give me this feedback because I know
this will help me. This is exactly what
I need.
Although my job is hard, I enjoy doing
this
on the exam day. you should make sure.
Okay, this is the last time I'm going to
talk about
for our generation. Let's find out movie
and talk about what they built. So, you
know, we were you were talking about
cinema for this.
[Music]
All right, Joseph, I went over this and
I have to say congratulations. You did a
phenomenal job. You use very good
fluency and coherency. You're relevant
in your terms. Um, you're giving great
examples, great explanations. I'm very
happy with that. Your vocabulary was off
the charts. Uh, even just with some
phrases you said here and there. Your
grammar was great. Uh, pronunciation was
definitely by far the best. Intonation
very good. your speech uh may be a
little bit more uh
pronounced, maybe more uh you know out
there, but overall I give you a nine.
That's a nine out of nine. I'd like to
say great job. Thank you very much.